DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：因果律 モビイ·ディック 大湿 時間軸：KoU 後期：水姬 壓制：沙夏 KoU
Hey, where are we going?
おーい　どこ行く気だよ？
I don't suppose we're
headed off to boil me in oil...
まさか　このまま
煮えたぎる油の中…　いや
or no, to push me off of a cliff...
崖っぷちから
突き落とすんじゃ…
あの～　メイドさん
Um... Miss Maid, would it
be okay if I used your bathroom?
おトイレとか
貸してもらえますか？
And when I do, I'm out of here.
その隙に逃げてやる
Ah, forgive me for saying so,
but I will just clean it up afterward,
ああ　はばかりでございますか
私が後でお掃除いたしますので
ご自由に　おもらしください
so please feel free to
let loose right where you are.
"Room of Boundlessness"
Look, I have not brought you
here to torture you, or anything.
なに　別に拷問にかけるために
連れてきたわけではない
You may rest at ease.
安心するがいい
道場？
A dojo?!
武具は　こちらに置いてある
The weapons are arranged over here.
Weapons?
武具？
好きなものを選ぶがよい…
Choose whichever one you like.
Or if you prefer,
you may fight barehanded.
何なら素手でも構わんが
ちょっと待て　それって…
Hold on a minute! You mean...
Why don't we settle
once and for all which one of us...
どちらが礼弥を守る資格の
ある者なのか
...is better qualified to protect Rea?
決着を　つけようではないか
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
Shiyo Transportation
お金は払ってもらえそうだな
It looks like I am
going to be paid, huh?
Welcome home, Mistress.
お帰りなさいませ　お嬢様
My father... Please call my father!
父を…　父を呼んでください
I am terribly sorry.
申し訳ございません
Master Dan'ichiro is
quite busy at the moment.
団一郎様は　ただ今
お取り込み中でございます
Furuya is here, too, right?
I'm going to go see my father!
降谷君も　いるのでしょう？
"Nothing... Really... Special"
私は父のもとへ向かいます
I'm afraid you cannot.
そうは　まいりません
Mistress Rea, we must first ask you
礼弥様には　しばしの間
おくつろぎいただきとう
ございます
to make yourself at home for a little while.
ウフフ
Excuse me...
失礼します
亞里亞様　礼弥様が
保護されたそうです
Madam Aria, Mistress Rea
is in our care once again.
Oh?
そう
お会いになられますか？
Would you like to see her?
Why?
何で？
え…
何で私が
あの子に会わないといけないの？
Why must I go and see that girl?
What?!
何？　何で　こんなこと…
Why are you doing this?
申し訳ございません
団一郎様の　ご命令ですので
I'm so very sorry.
We are under orders from Master Dan'ichiro.
In that case,
I'm giving you an order, too!
それでは私も命令します
今すぐこれを　ほどきなさい！
Take these off of me, at once!
Oh, my, imagine,
Mistress Rea giving us an order
あらあら　礼弥様が
そんな怖い顔して　ご命令だなんて
with such a stern look on her face...
It has only been a few
days since she ran away,
たった数日　家出されただけで
こうも　お変わりになられるとは
and already, she has changed this much.
This will not do, will it?
これは　いけませんねえ
少しくらい団一郎様には内緒で
Perhaps it would be okay if
we were to punish her just a little,
おきゅうを据えても
いいんじゃないかしら？
without Master Dan'ichiro knowing about it.
You're right. I doubt we will
ever get another chance like this.
そうですわね　こんな機会
二度とはないでしょうし
What... What are you going to do?!
何？　何する気ですか？
N-No...!
いやッ
まあ～！
カワイ～イ～
- How cute!
W-What is this?
What is the meaning of this?
なッ　何ですか
どういうことです！？　これは
We've always wanted to dress you
up like that, Mistress Rea!
いつか礼弥様に
着せてみたいと思ってたのよね
We knew you were sure to look good in it!
絶対　似合うと思ってたのよねえ
卑怯者　身動きを封じておいて
You cowards! How can you
pull this kind of mischief on someone
イタズラに人をもてあそぶなんて
恥を知りなさい
when they can't even move?!
Have you no shame?!
いや～
照れてる礼弥様も　カワイイ！
Mistress Rea even looks
cute when she's self-conscious!
What should we dress her up as next?
次　何着せてみる
A lady ninja? A stuffed animal?
くノ一？　着ぐるみ？
- We have to dress her up in this.
もう　こんなことしてる場合じゃ
ないのに
- Geez... I don't have time for this right now...
- We have to dress her up in this.
- No, wouldn't this be better?
胸騒ぎがする　降谷君…
I'm getting a bad feeling... Furuya...!
Furuya...!
降谷君！
Hmm? What's the matter?
うん？　どうした？
一撃でも
私に入れることができたなら
I told you, if you can
hit me with even one strike,
貴様の勝ちにしてやると
言ってるのだ
I will concede that you are the winner.
This doesn't really seem fair.
I don't know anything about fencing.
何かズルくね？
俺フェンシング知らないんだけど
Then choose whichever sword fighting
なら　貴様の得意とする剣術
格闘技で構わん
or combat style you are best at.
I can't do anything like that!
俺　そういうの何もできねえっての
何だ　貧弱な男だ
What? What a poor excuse for a man you are!
Do you mean you've never
learned the means to defend yourself?
護身術すら
学んでおらんというのか
Why would Rea want
to go to someone like you,
どうして　こんな才能も
技能もないようなヤツのもとへ
with neither talent nor technique?
礼弥は行こうとしたのだろうか
Huh?
You don't even know that.
そんなことも分かんねえんだ
うん？
Hmm?
You don't even know that!
そんなことも分かんねえんだ
そんなことも分かんねえんだ！
きゃ～
アリですよ　アリ
That's it! That's it!
Hyper-cute!
超カワイイ～
Y-You guys, let me go!
あなた達　ほどきなさい！
ですから　そのご命令に従うことは
As we told you,
we cannot follow your orders.
できません
No, we cannot.
The lady ninja next, right?
次はやっぱ　くノ一でしょ
Well then, let's do the stuffed animal after.
その次は着ぐるみにして
Yes, we'll see what happens...
そうねえ　どうしようかしら
Huh? Aren't we taking turns?
え～　順番じゃないんですか
- We'll see how things go, okay?
- I'm not wearing... either of them.
どちらも　着ません
えッ？
I...
私は
行かなければならないんです！
...have to be going!
Yeah, I think so, too...
俺も　そう思うんだけどさ
うん？　そうそう
Yeah, yeah!
What are you trying to say?
何が　言いたい？
What I'm saying is...
だから　つまり
...this is sucky.
きんもい
何ッ？
What?!
Settle this, one-on-one? What is this?
１対１で決着をつけよう？
何それ？
Picking a winner this way,
without taking Rea's feelings into account?
礼弥の気持ち関係なく　勝ち負けで
どっちかのものにするとか
And you, dragging me here against
my will to say what you've got to say
そもそも一方的に連れて来て
そんなこと言ったりとか
is pretty self-righteous in
the first place, is what I'm saying.
ひとりよがりだっての
For that matter, taking naked
pictures of your own daughter
ていうか　娘の誕生日に
裸の写真撮るのが趣味とか～
on her birthday is your idea of a hobby?
H-How the hell do you know that?
き…　貴様　なぜそれを！？
Usually, that's unheard-of, you know?
普通　ありえねえよな
親子愛とか　ブッ超えてんじゃん
Far beyond any father-daughter love.
Anyone would normally want to get away
そりゃ誰だって
こんなヤバい親父から
from an awful old man like you, right?
離れたいって思うっしょ　普通
降谷君
Furuya...!
つうわけで　冗談は置いといて
So let's just set the jokes aside,
forget about who is protecting
Rea, or who has any talent,
礼弥を誰が守るとか
才能がどうとか
and how about we concern
ourselves with what Rea wants to do?
そんなことより
まず礼弥が　どうしたいかだろ
アイツの人生に関して　アイツ不在で
決めていいことなんて何もねえよ
There's nothing you can
decide when it comes to her life
when she's not even there.
Clear and Serene as Still Water
That's what's most out of whack here.
その辺がまずズレてんだよ　大体
礼弥を守るって言ってたけど
You talk about protecting Rea,
ホントはアンタが礼弥を
手放したくないだけじゃないのか
but really, you just don't want
to let Rea out of your grip, do you?
あの母親から聞いたよ
礼弥だって　つらいと思うぜ
I heard all about it from her mom.
It must be hard on Rea,
the way you're always trying to project
アンタが　ずっと死んだ妻の面影を
アイツに重ね続けようとしてるのは
the image of your late
wife onto her like you do.
だから　もう…
So why don't you...
降谷よ
少々　私を　なめすぎたようだな
Furuya, it seems that you
took me a bit too lightly, doesn't it?
貴様の存在など
散華一族の力があれば
With the power available to the Sanka family,
your existence can be easily erased.
容易に消すことができるのだぞ
なあ　礼弥よ
Right, Rea?
Furuya...!
降谷君…
Whoa, he ran him through!
うわッ　刺さってるし
シッ！
Shh!
What's the matter, Furuya?
どうした？　降谷
本気で刺すとは思わなかったか？
Did you think I wasn't serious
about running you through?
ぐわッ
In your face.
何だと～
What was that?!
I got my licks in.
一矢報いたぜ
Furuya...?
降谷君…
あれ？　礼弥　何でここに？
Huh? Rea? What are you doing here?
て　おま…　その格好
えッ？
A-And in that outfit...?
ほお～！
その組み合わせがあったか
You can match those things up!
"Undead Bunny Zombie"
This rivals even zombie nurses...
No, this is even hotter!
ナースゾンビっ娘に匹敵
いや　それ以上に万萌え～！
No... the head maid
forced me to wear this...
いや　これはメイド長に無理やり…
わっふ　わわ…
Wait, Furuya, you're bleeding!
降谷君　血　血！
あッ？
Furuya!!
降谷～！
How can you not be affected?!
なぜ　貴様　平気なのだーッ？
Yeah... How, indeed?
ああ　何でだろうな
I'm not too sure, myself, but maybe
it's because I'm so worked up,
俺にも　よく分かんねえけど
興奮してアドレナリンが
分泌されてるからかな　それとも…
and my adrenaline is pumping. Or maybe...
It couldn't be...
まさか　あの時
Back there, when Rea licked my wound...
礼弥に傷口をなめられたことで
It would seem that I have
been "infected" by Rea's "poison."
どうやら俺は礼弥の毒に
感染してしまっていたようだな
Poison? Infected?
毒？　感染…
It's anesthetizing the pain,
but my heart is still beating,
痛覚は麻痺してるが
まだ心臓は動いてるってことは
which means that I haven't
received a lethal dose.
致死量の毒は
回ってないってことか
Well, I guess you can call me...
じゃあ　さしずめ
...a "half-zombie."
ハーフゾンビってとこか
A zombie, you say?
ゾンビだと？
In that case...
ならば
首を飛ばしてやる！
I'll take off your head!
Please, stop, already...
もう　やめてください
お父様
Father.
That last strike should have settled your score.
先の一撃で
もう決着はついていたはずです
But if you still wish to continue fighting,
それでも　まだ戦うのであれば
you will have to take me on, now!
今度は私が　お相手します！
What are you saying, Rea?
何を言う　礼弥
私は
I... just want to save you.
ただ　お前を救いたいのだ
I just want to cure you... of this
"unknown illness" that afflicts you.
お前が患ってしまった未知の病を
ただ
治してあげたいだけなのだ
Let's relocate ourselves to America.
一緒にアメリカに移り住もう
I've already made
arrangements for our passage.
渡航の手配も済ませてある
If we gather the greatest
doctors and researchers
世界各地から集めた
名医　研究者に頼めば
from around the world,
they might be able...
あるいは　いや　必ず
no, they are sure to be
able to find a treatment for you.
治療法が見つかるはずだ
Can that boy truly save you?
その男が本当に
お前を救えるのか？
How much can a single kid
with limited resources and knowledge
財力も知識も限られた小僧１人に
どの程度のことができる？
really do for you?
No, Father.
いいえ　お父様
別に
I don't really want to be cured.
私　治らなくてもいいんです
What...? If we don't do something,
your body will continue to...
何…　そのままでは　お前の体は
If it means having to
leave this town to be cured,
治すために
この町を離れるくらいなら
then I'd rather stay put.
このままでいいです
And even if it's only for a short time,
短い間だけだとしても
この町で降谷君と
一緒にいられれば　それだけで
as long as I can stay in this
town with Furuya, it's good enough.
Rea...
礼弥
But why...?
なぜだ
You're... content with just this small,
immediate amount of freedom?
お前…　こんな目先の
小さな自由程度でいいのか？
You're a special, dignified young lady.
お前は　特別で気高い存在なのに
Don't you get it yet, Father?!
まだ　分かんねえのか？　お父様！
Fath...
お父…
礼弥がホントに求めてるのは
Being "special" is not
something that Rea is really after!
特別なんかじゃない！
How many times have you ever let
Rea have what she wanted?!
今まで礼弥が自ら望んだことを
いくつ　かなえてあげた？
アンタの押し付けじゃなくてッ
And not what you forced on her?!
Father!
お父様～
I found a snail over in the gardens!
お庭で
かたつむりを見つけました
Listen to me, Rea, you
mustn't touch such filthy things.
いいかい　礼弥
お前は　あんな
汚れたものを触ってはいけない
I want to go out shopping with my friends.
お友達と
お買い物にでかけたいんです
そんなことをしなくても　私が
好きなものを買ってあげよう
You don't have to do that.
I will buy you whatever you like.
Tell me. Hmm?
言いなさい　うん？
Rea is already in high school, is she?
礼弥も　もう高校生か
あの子の周りに
We have to make sure that all the
lowbrow mates around her keep away.
低俗なヘテロが
近寄らんようにせんと
After all, Rea will only be
accepting one set of genes.
なぜなら　礼弥が受け入れるべき
遺伝子は　ただひとつ
Rea... just...
礼弥は　ただ
...wants to be a normal girl!
普通の女の子に
なりたいだけなのに！
Is that really the only reason...
本当に　それだけ…
Is that the only reason... why you died?
それだけのために
お前は死んだというのか
It was... my fault...?
私の　せいで…
It was... my...
私の…
Then again, I do agree
with a part of what you said.
でも俺　アンタの言ってたことには
一部賛成だわ
Huh?
It's true, there may be some things
確かに俺１人の力じゃ
that I can't do anything about on my own.
どうにもならないことが
あるかもしれない
So... when those come up,
I'd like to have us work together.
だから　その時には
アンタにも協力してほしいんだ
礼弥には　この先も
ずっと　ここにいてほしいから
Because I do want Rea
to stay here from now on.
Furuya...
降谷君…
Rea...
礼弥よ
本当に後悔しないのだな？
You're sure you have no regrets?
Yes.
はい
All right.
分かった
Furuya...
降谷よ
I leave Rea to you.
貴様に礼弥を預けよう
P-Pops...
オッサン…
お父様
Father...
However, only temporarily,
ただし　私が海外で礼弥を
治す方法を探す間　一時的にだ
while I am overseas,
looking for a way to cure Rea.
ずっと　任せるわけではない
I'm not letting you have her forever.
分かってるよ
それから
All right.
One more thing...
だからといって
礼弥の貞操を奪うことは許さんぞ
That doesn't mean I will allow
you to deprive her of her chastity.
I-I wouldn't do that!
ね…　ねーよ　そんなこと！
えッ　何言われたんですか？
Huh? What did he say to you?
えッ　いや　別に
そ…　そんなんじゃねえよ
Oh, nothing. N-Not what you're thinking!
But then, thank goodness...
for the time being...
でも　まあ良かった
これで　とりあえず…
Rea and I can live...
together... again...
礼弥と
また一緒に暮らすことが…
Furuya?!
降谷君　降谷君？
Furuya! Furuya!
降谷君！　いやあ～！
お飲み物は？
いらん
Would you care for a drink?
No.
Thank goodness!
良かった～！
あッ　いでででで…
あッ　ごめんなさい
Ow-w-w-w!
Oh, I'm sorry!
Wha...? Huh? I can feel pain again.
あれ？　痛覚が戻ってる
そうか　体内の毒がもう切れたのか
S-So that's it. The "poison" in
my system is all used up. Damn it...
チクショー
応急処置は
We performed first aid for you.
私達がしておきました
どうやら
It would appear that you've come back to life.
生き返ったようですのう
ていうか　死んでねえよ
Yeah, but I was never dead.
痛ッ…
とにかく良かったです
In any case, this is great.
You lost so much blood,
たくさん血が出たから
もう目が覚めないかと思って
I wasn't sure that you would ever wake up.
Oh, right. Sorry to make you worry like that.
そっか　心配かけたんだな　ごめん
Not at all.
いいえ
So, what's with that outfit?
つーか　その格好…
えッ　あッ　これは
Huh? Oh, this is...
The maids all said
"Furuya would be tickled," so...
メイドの皆さんに
降谷君が　きっと喜ぶからって
So, um, don't you like it?
その…　ダメですか？
ナースゾンビさん
A nurse zombie! Outstanding!
すんごく　いいです
Brother is such a pushover.
に－なんてイチコロよのう
Chihiro!
千紘～！
げッ　わんこ！？
Eep! Wanko!
You dummy, dummy, dummy!
バカバカバカ！　萌路ちゃんから
大ケガしたって聞いたから
I heard from Mero
that you were seriously hurt,
so I dashed right over!
飛んできたんだぞ
ケガのこと知ってるなら
If you know I'm hurt,
don't jump on top of me!
飛びつくなよ
あッ　ごめん
Ah, sorry. But never mind me,
how on Earth did this happen?
それより　一体どうして　こんな？
あ…　いや…
Oh, well...
Ah, I...
す…　すみませんでした
I'm sorry. This is all... my fault.
私が全て悪いんです
Eh? Why are you dressed as a nurse?
えッ　何でナースの格好？
Oh, I wore this to please Furuya.
あッ　これは降谷君が喜ぶからって
はあ？
Huh?! Hey, what did you make her do, you sicko?!
ちょっと
何やらせてんのよ　ド変態！
I'm not the one who made her do it!
俺が　やらせたわけじゃねえよ
でも喜んでたのう
But you were pleased, huh?
Oh, hell, yeah...
そりゃあ　もう…　何言わすんだよ
へえ～
Wait, why did you make me admit that!
Uh-huh...
Whatever the case, I am entirely responsible
とにかく
降谷君がこんなことになったのは
for Furuya ending up like this.
全て私の責任ですから
礼弥　いらんことは…
Rea, nobody asked you!
Miss Sanka, is it? You're the
zombie who's living here with them?
散華さんだっけ？
確か　ゾンビで居候してる…
Uh, yes.
あッ　はい…
Ah, we haven't been
properly introduced yet, have we?
あッ　まだ
ちゃんと挨拶してなかったね
I'm Saoji Ranko,
and I'm one year ahead of you.
私は１個年上の左王子蘭子
あ…　よろしく
Ah, it's a pleasure.
I'm Chihiro's older sister, and fiancée.
千紘の姉で　いいなずけです
どはあ～
Naturally I mean, his "human" one.
もちろん　人間の
You get it, right? That was a joke!
分かってるよな　今のジョークだぞ
Come on... Miss Wanko...
You've got to watch what you say!
ほら　わんこ…さん
適当なこと言うなっての
Huh? But when we were in grade
school, you promised, didn't you?
え～　でもさ
小学生の頃に約束したじゃん
Huh?
千紘
Chihiro!
What?
なーに？
Will you be my fiancé?
私の　いいなずけになる？
What's that?
何それ？
いいから　なりなさい！
Just say you will be!
Hmm, okay, I will.
う～ん　じゃあ　なる
I don't remember any of
our chatter from back then!
覚えてねえよ　そんな頃の雑談
Gotcha.
なんちゃって　ごめんね散華さん
Sorry, Miss Sanka. But did you
see how nervous Chihiro just got?
でも今の見た？　千紘のオロオロ具合
ウケるよねえ
Hilarious, isn't he?
Shut up! You were this close to
crying a moment ago, weren't you?!
うるせえ　お前だって
さっき半泣きだったろーが
Oh, that was just an act.
あれ演技なんですけど
嘘くせえな　てか俺も演技だけど
You're such a liar!
And hey, I was just acting, too!
In that case, you're a failure.
だったら不合格
Though, you know...
てかさ
うぐッ
I'd love to hear how this all happened.
いきさつを
聞かせてもらいましょうか
Let go of me, and I'll tell you.
これ　といたら話してやるよ
それは　できませ～ん
I'm afraid I can't do that!
そっか　この人
- So that's it. She's...
- Ow-w-w-w!
...in love with Furuya...
降谷君のことが
好き　なんだ…
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
I see. So Mero has quit, then.
そうですか
萌路ちゃん降りちゃったんですね
What can you do? She's still just
a child, after all. Let's do it.
しょうがねえよ
アイツも　まだ子供だからさ
行くか
はい
Right!
Next time on Sankarea, episode 12:
次回　さんかれあ　第１２話
"At That Moment... I..."
あの瞬間　俺は…
E-Everybody watch mero!
みんな　見るメロ！
Mero!
萌路！
萌路ちゃんッ
Mero!
I'm not running away anymore.
もう　逃げたりせぬわ